<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Development Phases</title>
		<author email="ykryshchuk@n-ix.com.ua">Yuriy Kryshchuk</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Development Phases">

			<p>In order to speed up introducing the Baxter Configuration Server in production, it
				has been decided to implement the application in few phases. Each phase will extend
				its superior with additional features. </p>

			<p> The PoC shown by Yuriy was a working example with current price engine code. It's
				content was:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>basic editor for properties.xml and log4j.xml</li>
				<li>basic versioning possibility</li>
				<li>configuration file delivery to different nodes</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Based on ideas highlighted in PoC and discussion we had we defined the first goal to
				achieve:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Implementing a basic configuration facade (future extensibility)</li>
				<li>Implementing the configuration file delivery</li>
				<li>Implementing identification of components (e.g. blotter 1,2,x)</li>
				<li>Benefits: <ul>
						<li>One place editing – avoid inconsistency</li>
						<li>Changes can be easily audited, tracked by using a VCS</li>
					</ul>
				</li>
			</ul>

			<p>Further development possibilities:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Implementing configuration editor</li>
				<li>Implementing validation of configuration</li>
				<li>Implementing a unified launcher for components</li>
			</ul>

			<p>Action points:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Yuiry will create a requirement list based on first declared goal</li>
				<li>We refine the requirement list, and we estimate the amount of work</li>
				<li>We implement the soluiton</li>
			</ul>

			<subsection name="Phase 1">
				<p>This phase is targeted to Baxter Price Engine. </p>
				<p>The goal of first phase is to build the centralized configuration storage for
					Price Engine components and re-factor those components to use this storage. No
					management UI is expected. No support for configuration revisions. It should be
					the simplest solution that allows to avoid the redundancy of configuration
					sources among the same environment. Operating personal will manage configuration
					by means of manual editing of files. </p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Phase 2">
				<p>This phase is targeted to Baxter Price Engine. </p>
				<p>The goal of this phase is to develop a graphical UI to manage the configuration.
					There should be possibility to manage configuration revisions. </p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Phase 3">
				<p>This phase extends support of other Baxter products. </p>
				<p>This phase adds support for other products, like ABOS, CD etc. It includes
					integration of those products with Baxter Configuration. </p>
			</subsection>

		</section>

	</body>

</document>
