<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Configuration Processors</title>
		<author email="ykryshchuk@n-ix.com.ua">Yuriy Kryshchuk</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Overview">
			<p>Configuration processor is a component responsible for building thte configuration
				file from configuration sources.</p>
			<p>Each Baxter product provides its own Configuration Processor that is specific for
				Product configuration domain. See <a href="packaging.html">packaging rules</a> for
				processors.</p>
			<p>Configuration Server also provides the instruments (Java Classes and Transformation
				Stylesheets) to be reused by Product's Configuration Processors.</p>
			<p>The format of the processor descriptor can be found <a href="descriptor"
				>here</a>.</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Predefined Processors">
			<p>The Configuration Server provides the implementation for several predefined
				configuration processors. Each product may use these processors in their descriptors
				or extend the existing processors.</p>

			<subsection name="As Is Processor">

				<code>com.baxter.config.processor.impl.AsIsProcessor</code>

				<p>The purpose of this processor is to deliver the configuration source as it is,
					that is, without any transformation or modification. Typical usage of such a
					processor would be to return the binary configuration files.</p>

				<p>In order to use this processor you define it in descriptor as following: </p>
				<source> &lt;processor class="com.baxter.config.processor.impl.AsIsProcessor" type="bin"
					/&gt; </source>
				<p>Then you can request a configuration file with URL:
						<code>http://localhost/config/com.baxter.demo/myfile.dat/bin</code> this
					will return a source <code>myfile.dat</code> without any modifications. </p>

			</subsection>

			<subsection name="XSLT Processor">

				<code>com.baxter.config.processor.impl.XSLTProcessor</code>

				<p>As the name implies it is supposed to transform the input sources with XSLT using
					the specified XSL template. In the processor package each processor is
					responsible for some configuration type, e.g. processor for log4j, for logback,
					for Price Engine Properties XML, etc.</p>

				<p>In order to use this processor you define it in descriptor as following: </p>
				<source> &lt;processor class="com.baxter.config.processor.impl.XSLTProcessor"
					type="log4j"&gt; &lt;parameter name="xsl"&gt;log4j.xsl&lt;/parameter&gt;
					&lt;/processor&gt; </source>
				<p>Then you can request a configuration file with URL:
						<code>http://localhost/config/com.baxter.demo/my-component/log4j</code> this
					will return transformation result obtained with <code>log4j.xsl</code> template. </p>
				<p>The default implementation of XSLT Processor passes these input parameters to
					XSLT:</p>

				<ul>
					<li>configurationProductId</li>
					<li>configurationVersion</li>
					<li>configurationComponentId</li>
					<li>configurationVariant</li>
				</ul>

				<p>The stylesheet can access these parameters using the XSLT variable syntax
					${...}.</p>

				<p>The root stylesheet specified for the processor may import other stylesheets from
					the package, or it may import some predefined stylesheets from default
					processors implementation, in this case the urls must include protocol
						<code>baxterxsl</code>, for example, <code>baxterxsl:log4j.xsl</code>.</p>

				<p>In the stylesheet file you can import the other xsl files int this way.</p> 
				
				<source>
    				&lt;xsl:import href="baxterxsl:text-fmt.xsl"/&gt;
    				&lt;xsl:import href="inc/input-dump.xsl" /&gt;
    			</source>

				<p>The links will be resolved to</p>
				<p>/META-INF/config/xsl/text-fmt.xsl</p>
				<p>/META-INF/config/inc/input-dump.xsl</p>

				<p>Stylesheets may access all files available in the repository. The XSL is
					responsible for loading the proper file. Custom URI Resolver supports the
					protocol <code>baxterrepo</code>. For example, when XSL loads a file
						<code>baxterrepo:jms/nodes.xml</code>, and the current processor belongs to
					product <code>com.baxter.demo</code>, the file will be resolved to
						<code>CONFIG_REPO/com/baxter/demo/jms/nodes.xml</code>, where
						<code>CONFIG_REPO</code> is a path to configuration repository on
					filesystem.</p>
				
				<p>We can also use reference with full path by starting the path with / and with relative path.</p>
				
				<source>
					&lt;xsl:variable name="helloWorld" select="document('baxterrepo:/com/baxter/demo2/hello-world.xml')"/&gt;
					&lt;xsl:variable name="helloWorld" select="document('baxterrepo:subDir/hello-world.xml')"/&gt;
				</source>
				
				<p>The reference will be resolved as
					CONFIG_REPO/com/baxter/demo2/hello-world.xml
				while the other one will use the current product id <code>com.baxter.demo</code> and resolve the path as
					CONFIG_REPO/com/baxter/demo/subDir/hello-world.xm</p>
				

			</subsection>

		</section>

	</body>

</document>
