<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Configuration Server Concept</title>
		<author email="ykryshchuk@n-ix.com.ua">Yuriy Kryshchuk</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Concept">

			<p> The Configuration Server in its first implementation phase serves as only the
				provider of configuration files to the clients. </p>

			<img src="uml/concept.png" alt="Config Server Concept"/>

			<p>All configurations are persisted on local file system as set of XML files. These
				files are then read by a RestfulServlet and processed into a result file via XSLT. </p>

			<img src="uml/config-request-processing.png" alt="Config Request Processing"/>

			<subsection name="Processing">
				<p>The actual processing of configuration requests is delegated to Configuration
					Processors. That is, the RestfulServlet receives the request from a client and
					preprocesses it. The preprocessing includes parsing the configuration path and
					version. Then servlet requests the actual processor from the factory which is
					then called to actually build the configuration and deliver it to the
					client.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Getting the Processor">
				<p>Baxter Configuration server is supposed to serve configuration for different
					products, however, on the first iteration it will be implemented for Price
					Engine only. In order to achieve a kind of flexibility for supported
					configurations, the system introduces a <code>domain</code> or
						<code>processor</code> for a particular product. Each processor is fine
					tuned to serve the applications from its domain. </p>
				<p>At runtime all deployed processors are known to the Configuration Server (e.g. to
					the ProcessorsFactory). So, the target processor can be determined by the input
					request (as it contains the configuration product, component and type
					identification).</p>
				<p>In order to simplify the implementation and deployment of Configuration Server
					the Processors are organized in separate JAR files that are added to
					application's classpath. This implies application redeployment if processors
					change (adde new, changed existing, etc). Later this can be reviewed to support
					separate deployment of Product Configuration Processors without the need to
					restart the application. </p>
				<p>More information on processors structure can be found on <a
						href="../config-processor/">Processors Project Site</a>. </p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Processors">
				<p>When the processor is invoked for the client request the processor already has an
					information what kind of configuration is needed for a client. The processor is
					also aware of configuration source layout and schema. So, in simply satying the
					configuration processor is required to start the parametrized XSLT and return
					the result for caller.</p>
			</subsection>

		</section>

	</body>

</document>
