<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Configuration Protocol</title>
		<author email="ykryshchuk@n-ix.com.ua">Yuriy Kryshchuk</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Overview">

			<p>The RestfulServlet follows the REST idiom. When the client needs some configuration
				it builds a request that points to a configuration item on the server. When the
				request is processed on the server the response file is prepared and delivered to
				the client. From the client point of view the configuration server is a blackbox.
				Internally the server hosts configurations in a set of well defined files and uses
				this files to generate the final configuration file to be delivered.</p>

			<p>Every configuration item on the server can be uniquelly identified by its URL. That
				is a general rule implemented by Baxter Configuration Server.</p>

		</section>

		<section name="Configuration Items">

			<p>The Configuration Server hosts different configurations. These are formally the files
				to be delivered to the client. So, each configuration file has its absolute URL or
				coordinates. </p>

			<p>In general the URL pattern can be represented as following. All of the URL components
				will be explained in details below.</p>

			<code>&lt;config-base&gt;/rest/&lt;config-type&gt;/&lt;product-id&gt;/&lt;component-id&gt;[/&lt;variant&gt;][?version=&lt;config-version&gt;]</code>

			<p>Here are some samples for configuration requests.</p>

			<ul>
				<li>http://localhost:8080/config/log4j/com.baxter.pe/price-engine-dbserver?version=1.0</li>
				<li>http://localhost:8080/config/logback/com.baxter.pe/price-engine-broadcast</li>
				<li>http://localhost:8080/config/properties/com.baxter.pe/price-engine-blotterserver</li>
				<li>http://localhost:8080/config/asis/com.baxter.config/some-file-as-is.xml</li>
			</ul>

			<subsection name="Configuration Base">
				<code>&lt;config-base&gt;</code>
				<p>This is a base location of Configuration Web Application. For example,
						<code>http://config.baxter.com/config</code>. That is a URL to the
					Configuration web application root context.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Configuration Type">
				<code>&lt;config-type&gt;</code>
				<p>Determines what type of configuration is requested. The supported types of the
					configurations may vary between different products and components. Common types
					are log4j and logback.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Product ID">
				<code>&lt;product-id&gt;</code>
				<p>This is a Baxter Product identifier. It identifies to which product belongs the
					requested configuration. It should be typically the Maven's groupId of the
					application. For example, <code>com.baxter.pe</code></p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Component ID">
				<code>&lt;component-id&gt;</code>
				<p>This is a component identifier in a Baxter Product suite. It identifies to which
					component (application) belongs the requested configuration. It should be
					typically the Maven's artifactId of the application. For example,
						<code>price-engine-dbserver</code></p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Variant">
				<code>&lt;variant&gt;</code>
				<p>The Variant is a kind of extension of a typical configuration. It usually
					inherits all values from a base configuration and just extends or overrides some
					of them.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Configuration Version">
				<code>&lt;config-version&gt;</code>
				<p>The version required by the client. If ommited, then the current version is
					returned. If specified, then server ensures that delivered configuration version
					will be same or newer than requested value.</p>
			</subsection>

		</section>

	</body>

</document>
