<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Configuration Processors Packaging</title>
		<author email="ykryshchuk@n-ix.com.ua">Yuriy Kryshchuk</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Configuration Processors Packaging">
			<p>The Configuration Processors are organized as JAR archives with predefined structure.
				The archive contains processor descriptor file, default XML sources (default
				configuration), the transformation files (XSLT) and optional classes needed for
				processing. </p>
			<p>Following diagram shows a content of the Price Engine Configuration Processor
				JAR.</p>

			<img src="uml/package-structure.png" alt="Package Structure"/>

			<subsection name="META-INF/services">
				<p>This directory contains the processor descriptor file
						<code>org.yurconf.processor.xml</code>. The configuration factory will
					run these files in order to load processors.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="META-INF/config/default">
				<p>The directory contains a default configuration for the product. These are set of
					XML files which conform to the configuration layout for particular product.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="META-INF/config/xsl">
				<p>The set of transformation stylesheets used by processing to build the
					configurations from XML sources.</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="com/baxter/config/pe">
				<p>The root java package for custom classes.</p>
			</subsection>

		</section>

		<section name="Unpacking the package">
			<p>The Configuration Server hosts all configuration sources in the local configuration
				repository. The repository location can be specified in web context parameter named
					<code>com.baxter.config.Repository</code>, if the parameter has not been
				specified in <code>web.xml</code>, then default location
					<code>~/.baxter-configuration-repository</code> will be used by a server.</p>

			<p>When the server applciation starts it copies the default configuration from processor
				package into the repository. Once the default configuration has been copied it will
				remain there until the new configuration processor is deployed which contains an
				updated default configuration. This update may include new config sources, changed
				or extended sources. In order to keep the managed configuration on repository when
				doing the update, the server application implements different strategies to update
				existing files to new structure or layout.</p>
			<p>Here is an example what and how is copied, assume the product id is
					<code>com.baxter.demo</code>: <map id="default-config-copy">
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr>
								<th>Package JAR</th>
								<th>Configuration Repository</th>
							</tr>
						</thead>
						<tbody>
							<tr>
								<td>
									<code>META-INF/config/default/a.xml</code><br/>
									<code>META-INF/config/default/b.xml</code><br/>
									<code>META-INF/config/default/subdir/c.xml</code><br/>
									<code>META-INF/config/default/other/subdir/d.xml</code>
								</td>
								<td>
									<code>$REPO/com/baxter/demo/a.xml</code><br/>
									<code>$REPO/com/baxter/demo/b.xml</code><br/>
									<code>$REPO/com/baxter/demo/subdir/c.xml</code><br/>
									<code>$REPO/com/baxter/demo/other/subdir/d.xml</code>
								</td>
							</tr>
						</tbody>
					</table>
				</map>
			</p>
			<p>In addition to copying the default configuration files from JAR to repository, the
				descriptor file itself is also persisted in the Product's repository root. So if the
				product ID is <code>com.baxter.demo</code>, the descriptor will be copied to
					<code>$REPO/com/baxter/demo/.descriptor.xml</code>. This implies
				that each product has its own product ID to avoid the collisions between
				configuration descriptors in repository.</p>

		</section>

	</body>

</document>
